<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Everyone Has a Story</title>
    <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Everyone Has a Story</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 19:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://BhaveshSGupta.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
		
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthday Week 2019</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/birthday-week-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/birthday-week-2019/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So another Birthday gone as-usual. Although I am not a big celebrator expect last where we had a trip to Rishikesh on my birthday PS: I am yet to write that post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My celebration to birthday most part has only dinner with family. We go to a fancy hotel have some food and come back. Its almost like this has become a tradition to celebrate birthday this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post was to be published on 19th May, instead I am writing now because of my laziness I don&amp;rsquo;t often write due to fear of writing or fear of making mistakes while write. Although I plan to write and read more. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#readingeveryday 2</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/readingeveryday-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 18:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/readingeveryday-2/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/readingeveryday/&#34;&gt;#readingeveryday&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://zenhabits.net/reading/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; Today I dedicated 15 mins to read documentation or &lt;a href=&#34;https://pymbook.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34; title=&#34;pym&#34;&gt;pym&lt;/a&gt; python book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#Readingeveryday Day-1</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/readingeveryday-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 16:03:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/readingeveryday-1/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been having difficulties in making reading a habbit so my friend Jason, introduce to something which is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/readingeveryday/&#34;&gt;#readingeveryday&lt;/a&gt; challenge to start reading here is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://zenhabits.net/reading/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;. So this post and goes to that today is the day 1, rightnow as I am starting I am reading 15 min a day. Being a slow Reader I was able to read 6 pages of the book which I am currently &amp;ldquo;Think and Grow Rich&amp;rdquo; by Napoleon Hill.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Habit</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/reading-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 03:58:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/reading-habit/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am trying to develop the habit of reading. Recently while going through #dgplug summer training, there have been discussion about having a habit to read. You write 1/10th part of what you read. Reading and writing both is considered to be one of the most important part of engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So trying to follow above I started reading books still non-technical but as a first step I did start. I do a lot of technical reading, but I never write about it so one of the task is to start writting about technical readings be it github projects I am going to try to write about it. May be my writing speed gets better with time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Man Who Stole My Laptop&#39;s Ferrari</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/the-man-who-stole-my-laptops-ferrari/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 01:24:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/the-man-who-stole-my-laptops-ferrari/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, the story goes back to 2014-2015 maybe I don&amp;rsquo;t remember exactly when my laptop stopped working on later finding it was discovered the issue was with my onboard graphics card. A brief history I had a Sony Vaio laptop with AND Radeon graphics card on it. So, it was found that it was my graphics card which is creating issue. So, I took it to many people to check what can be done this that. Everyone was like your laptop won’t work or you need to do this and that. So, a friend of mine had a friend who was into laptop/computer&amp;rsquo;s business or something of that sort. So, he said let’s talk with him after inspecting he said it would cost around 6k, and it would be done. I was happy, I was not knowing much about hardware back then (although it says same even today but I know bit more). So, I gave him my laptop to get repaired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, when I got my laptop back I boot it up and was shocked to see that my processor is now Intel P4 which use to be Intel Core i5. So, I called the guy he said in Hindi and I quote &amp;ldquo;Bhaiya apko galat dikh rha hoga ek baar restart karo sahi dikhega&amp;rdquo;. I was like I know that much come-on. So, I went to his office he was like show me laptop. Then he called his repairmen saying have we changed processor for the laptop. His repairmen were like no I haven&amp;rsquo;t I have just changed motherboard and fit same processor and everything. And he added although I had seen this laptop was open previously may be someone had changed the processor during that time. And I was taken aback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, a man stole my laptop&amp;rsquo;s Ferrari and I don’t know who he is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript uses utf16 and Html utf8, then how things work together?</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/javascript-utf16-and-html-utf8-how-things-work-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 05:45:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/javascript-utf16-and-html-utf8-how-things-work-together/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This was part of one the discussion of dgplug discussion, that javascript uses utf-16 and html we usually use utf-8 as character encoding then how things work out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was quite intresting on how things work around because of this. So I was reading around to find answers for the above question and I landed upon &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/12114477/how-do-i-correctly-insert-unicode-in-an-html-title-using-javascript/12114520#12114520&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;. And this text from the answer in the link helps understand how things work. &amp;ldquo;JavaScript string constants are parsed by the JavaScript parser. Text inside HTML tags is parsed by the HTML parser. The two languages (and, by extension, their parsers) are different, and in particular they have different ways of representing characters by character code.&amp;rdquo; Basically they won&amp;rsquo;t have issue with different character encoding as they would render same character. More over javascript parser would parse the character into the html when you use innerHTML method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have to read more and update this post again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update 17 Jul 18</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/update-17-jul-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 05:03:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/update-17-jul-18/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;This update post was actually created on 10th july, But as ususal due to some x reason it is not yet complete. There are several things which are running into my life right now out of them on is to update this blog on regular bases to get align with things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pending-posts&#34;&gt;Pending Posts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog came to life again due to dgplug summer training where we were taught to write blog post about things you are doing or learning(PS: I am yet to read logs to that class :p).
- Although I was thinking to update this as regularly as much as possible even before the training started I had planned to write down as many as things possible starting from the birthday post. I am yet to write that which would be up soon.
- I need to coverup summer training so this time I don&amp;rsquo;t get leave behind many.
- One of the biggest confusion I have is about my career, as of now I am working as Front End Developer but I think I can&amp;rsquo;t do that for whole life moreover I don&amp;rsquo;t want to. I remember my college when I was not even aware about properties of body and div:P
- My competetive coding is also left behind, because of all the things around and me. I should work on that to asap tp get things align.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dgplug Start 2</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/dgplug-start-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 22:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/dgplug-start-2/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So Last year in some Facebook group or somewhere I read about summer training offered by dgplug on IRC chat. I had heard about IRC chat before and had tried to use it once or twice but never tried to use it or understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically summer trainings are usually for college students but during my college time I was too busy being in and around Microsoft Student Partner that I didn&amp;rsquo;t knew about many things around. More about dgplug – Linux User’s Group of Durgapur. An inside how awesome is internet, if you want to travel to Durgapur from Gandhidham(my place) it is 2160 km. This is year training started on 17 Jun and today its already 17 July, I am always late :-D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Year I was not able to complete training, or I should say I was not able to complete trainings due several issues. This year seems better still I am very far with things which are going around in training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The summer training of dgplug happens starts normally around June and it last for 3 months. One of the best things it almost covers every necessary thing starting from communications to developing/coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My progress this year is better than last year I think I had not even been into trainings for a month, I am very much behind then many students in training. One of the reason for this is my job timing which goes from 6:30 pm to 3:30 am. Training time is around 7 pm due to which I keep missing sessions and keep reading logs. But there is huge difference in reading logs later than during training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other issue I have is laptop, currently my current laptop doesn’t work as it should be so there are issue’s with giving time. I plan to buy a new laptop sooner.
One of the things I want to do which is being told in training is ability to read and write. I guess mbuf or Kushal (these are two of mentor who conducts summer training), where explaining that one should read at-least 25 pages a day of book. As an engineer one should be able to write in as descriptive as possible and should read. To get updated with things around it is necessary to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan every day to read at-least few pages of the current book I possess but still success is far. But future is bright. I am not a good writer, I have always issues in expressing things. This is one try, probably there would be more to make my writing skills even better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read More, Write More, and Learn even More.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static file blog using web based CMS</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/static-file-blog-with-web-based-cms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 12:44:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/static-file-blog-with-web-based-cms/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;So a few days back I was working on a solution so that I could keep that blog updated. As this is a not-self deployable blog I actually need to deploy changes. Somebody would say instead of taking so much efforts to deploy a single post you could have set up a WordPress blog which has an awesome app to add post, n number of themes, plugins, etc. But I feel I like it this way. The geeky way of maintaining a blog :D. I was working on to find something which could help me update my blog from cell phone. For that I was able to install git on my cellphone (SU access). First how this blog actually works so there are two repo&amp;rsquo;s using which this blog works. One is the content management part where the content stays, theme stays and other things. And there is another repo on which there whole hugo generated HTML stays which is present on github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was having git access into my cellphone I was able to update content but how to use hugo. I need to run hugo on my content repo and update the blog repo which was not possible through phone. So to do that what I was thinking was I would setup a server, when there would be a commit in content repo it would call a web-hook. The hook would work to fetch content from content repo into server, server would run hugo generate html and then it would push updates to blog repo and my blog would be live :D. This could be most tedious thing I would have thought to do for a blog. So I started again to find something which could be useful here as there are 1000&amp;rsquo;s of blog which actually uses hugo who would have faced the issue of updating blog post from mobile. There came one such solution which was &lt;a href=&#34;https://forestry.io&#34;&gt;forestry.io&lt;/a&gt;. Forestry is a static file CMS the thing I was needing to update my blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The awesome thing about forestry is that it allows you to use hugo and jekyll both with an online CMS like features. Also you can configure almost everything using their platform. I remember during my college days I was not having laptop and that time I was using jekyll blog. Jekyll has a tedious path to configure, you need ruby and other things to make it work. And to work on a windows it was a whole new challenge. If there had been something like forestry back then my blog would be having much more content :D. So forestry became solution for my misery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-was-doing-above&#34;&gt;Why I was doing above?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this year for my birthday I had a sort of planned/unplanned trip to Haridwar and rishikesh. And I was thinking to keep things updated using the blog which I was not able to due to network issue, battery issue, internet issue and finally I lost my phone basically someone pick my pocket :(.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying Forestry from mobile browser</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/trying-forestry-from-mobile-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 05:59:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/trying-forestry-from-mobile-browser/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first post using forestry I have actually setup git for android and other stuff for my blog this is another approach which can be used let see how&amp;rsquo;s this work. There would be more test post to check the overall working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bbye&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kudos&lt;br /&gt;
Bhavesh Gupta&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bloging from mobile</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/mobile-test-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 05:20:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/mobile-test-post/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the solution test for the question how to create static site generator blog from mobile with an ease this is a test post of everything works out a how to post is comming down soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;kudos,
bye&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally HTTPS</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/finally-https/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 02:22:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/finally-https/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, GitHub started providing HTTPS even for custom domain, So I had to enable that plus there were some internal changes which were required. Which I had done. Its been almost two years since I have bought this domain But I have been away from blogging. I had setup this a good time ago using Hugo and a cactus theme still have been struck the same place not able to write what I want or I should say not able to give to write what I want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, there is a lot been going in with me, in personal and professional life. I am going to spend a bit of more time here, in writing things both technical and personal, would try to write down more and more stuff so that I can take my mind of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool, this is, for now, let us see whether is this setup work fine and would do more config if require. Till then peace out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hasura Product Development Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/hasura-internship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 15:28:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/hasura-internship/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hasura Product Development Fellowship So Introduction to Modern App Development(IMAD) was one of the MOOC that is was recently part of as the title says it was basic introduction to app development where we learnt several things including node, git, Android app development, Mac app development, etc. The fellowship was offered to the top students from the IMAD course(I was one of them ;). The fellowship is all about learning how to make your own product as it is developed in the industry following development process starting from deciding about the idea then prototyping then data modeling and so on. The whole fellowship is divided into an 8-week program, which was offered in two batches May-Jun and Jun-Jul batch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is around 5-6 week running and because of several problems with my laptop and several office stuff, I am kinda running late. One of the reasons for being late is also this blog(yes wired right! read along). I have created several blogs before or I should start and never care to look at it. Being Software Engineer or I just said Computer Science Graduate I wanted my blog to be hosted and completely managed my me so that I can tweak and detail to smallest as and when I want to. So this blog is created using &lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Opens in a new window&#34; href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to create a complete my own theme but it was taking more time than I has thought so here I am using an enhanced cocoah-eh theme. I am changing theme according to my requirement may be I may release it someday when I am satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/first-post/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So finally blog is up again I have thinking to making this up long time and finally I have yay. Well I did purchase the domain in last august, I am using hugo static site generator and currently I am using customized version of cocoa-eh theme. What I like about this theme is its very simple, plain, I dont like more fancy stuff and I could customize it as per requirement. Although I need to work a lot on this to make it more awesome and release cooca-eh-eh :-D (You never know).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially I was thinking of using medium or blogger as the way of creating the blog, then I thought I needed a self hosted blog(Being geek). I had many options for using several different things like Jekyll, Hexo, Hugo and many more. I have used jekyll before and so with a desire to explore something new I am hugo for this. The awesome thing about hugo is that its really fast plus, there is no installation require for using hugo its just a executable(exe) file and we are done replace the exe file the newer file and we are done with update. Still there are several things that I need to learn about hugo and I would be doing that for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After being in web/front-end development for a while and making several website&amp;rsquo;s, now I have good amount of knowledge about SEO, page load, things to keep in mind etc. all this would be helpful in this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
