<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bhavesh Gupta</title>
    <link>http:BhaveshSGupta.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bhavesh Gupta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017 Bhavesh Gupta </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 12:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http:BhaveshSGupta.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>http:BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/first-post/</guid>
      <description>So finally blog is up again I have thinking to making this up long time and finally I have yay. Well I did purchase the domain in last august, I am using hugo static site generator and currently I am using customized version of cocoa-eh theme. What I like about this theme is its very simple, plain, I dont like more fancy stuff and I could customize it as per requirement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>http:BhaveshSGupta.me/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:BhaveshSGupta.me/home/</guid>
      <description>This is the home page. It will display the blog section if there is one, and a text before.
Hey ! Welcome to the Cocoa Enhanced theme. Here are some articles :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>http:BhaveshSGupta.me/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:BhaveshSGupta.me/license/</guid>
      <description>You can use this page to put a license on the contents of your blog, like so:
 The MIT License (MIT)
Copyright &amp;copy; 2015 Nishanth Shanmughamnishanth.gerrard@gmail.com
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>