<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>js on Everyone Has a Story</title>
    <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/tags/js/</link>
    <description>Recent content in js on Everyone Has a Story</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 19:54:55 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://BhaveshSGupta.me/tags/js/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Convert Excel to Json</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/convert-excel-to-json/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 19:54:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/convert-excel-to-json/</guid>
      <description>Some time in our projects we need data in json files(mostly web projects). But collecting and managing data in json files is harder(At least this is what I feel) compared to excel. I had recently ran into a similar situation where I need some data. Data is going to be provided by a non-technical person/client. And there going to be several rounds of it.
So I was looking for options what can be done here, where I found several online tools which could be used for same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object-Oriented Programming With JavaScript (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/object-oriented-programming-with-javascript-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 16:56:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/object-oriented-programming-with-javascript-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started to learn Object-oriented Programming in JavaScript using this &lt;a href=&#34;https://udemy.com/javascript-object-oriented-programming/&#34;&gt;course&lt;/a&gt;. This post is more of notes for the course I am taking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript uses utf16 and Html utf8, then how things work together?</title>
      <link>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/javascript-utf16-and-html-utf8-how-things-work-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 05:45:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://BhaveshSGupta.me/blog/javascript-utf16-and-html-utf8-how-things-work-together/</guid>
      <description>This was part of one the discussion of dgplug discussion, that javascript uses utf-16 and html we usually use utf-8 as character encoding then how things work out.
This was quite interesting on how things work around because of this. So I was reading around to find answers for the above question and I landed upon this. And this text from the answer in the link helps understand how things work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
